CHI-MEI WANG

Hilltop Komazawa 304, 4-21-14, Nozawa, Setagaya-ku, Tokyo, 154-0003

070-3992-8633 | chimei.wang.jp@gmail.com



https://github.com/Wangchimei

PROFILE

I am currently learning web development at DIVE INTO CODE, a programming school located in Tokyo, and graduated in December 2019. I have experience with both frontend and back-end using Ruby.

With prior experience in marketing and client services, I am capable of working collaboratively and individually. I worked as a marketing researcher at Kantar TNS, one of the largest research agencies worldwide, for about two years. After moving to Tokyo and dedicating six months to learning Japanese, I worked as an assistant manager at Aim Services, where I was responsible for sales analysis and global client services.

I am self-motivated, enthusiastic, eager to learn, and willing to grow continuously. I am seeking an opportunity to contribute quality work, hone my programming skills, and be able to share my knowledge with others.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AIM Services Co., LTD. - Tokyo, Japan

July 2017 - Aug 2019

Assistant Manager

- Created monthly profit/loss and sales reports, and further analyzed and interpreted sales data to adjust business plans for growth
- Identified highly-correlated products to optimize product placement, resulting in an increase in average customer spending by 15%
- Arranged events on a monthly basis to attract potential customers, build recognition, and generate revenue, which increased average number of customers per day by 30%
- Reported to clients' global teams to share and update performance and future planning
- Managed incoming local and international client requests and coordinated with local vendors to provide service that suited their needs
- Organized and optimized shift scheduling in order to promote costeffectiveness

Kantar TNS (WPP Group) - Taipei, Taiwan

Nov. 2014 - July 2016

Research Executive

- Supported the Research Manager with liaising and communicating with clients during the course of projects to tailor the research to best meet their needs
- Established connections with clients by following up with them and ensuring satisfaction for future business opportunities
- Worked closely with teams from different divisions, as well as international teams, and communicated frequently and clearly in order to increase the accuracy of work to decrease time inefficiency
- Monitored the progress and quality of fieldwork, flagged and resolved potential issues, and escalated problems to ensure individual project deadlines were met
- Assisted in research planning and survey program pre-testing in order to eliminate any logic problems and ensure data credibility
- Assisted in research reports, communicated findings to the research manager and director, and delivered consultancy and actionable insights to clients

Hsiang-An Machinery Corp. – Kaohsiung, Taiwan

Jan. 2010 - Jan. 2012

Administrative Specialist

- Handled incoming inquiries from both existing and potential clients to understand their needs and convert into future business
- Planned, scheduled and prioritized project timelines to monitor progress and ensure clients' deadlines were met
- Followed up with clients to ensure satisfaction and a strong working relationship
- Identified administration issues and resolved them to enhance office operations

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Marketing - Florida, USA

Jan. 2012 - Aug. 2014

University of South Florida

GPA:3.87/4.00

Bachelor of Arts in Finance – Taipei, Taiwan

Sept. 2005 - June 2009

Shih Hsin University

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Vue.js

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Firebase

Git/GitHub, AWS S3

SKILLS

Languages:

Chinese (Native) / English (Fluent) / Japanese (Fluent)

Computer:

MS Office – Word, Excel, PowerPoint (Advanced)

PROJECTS

TripHub

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Amazon S3, Google Maps API, Unsplash API

A graduation project at DIVE INTO CODE.

This web app was created for travel enthusiasts to share their past travel schedules, plan their own schedules, and share pictures and feedback.

GitHub repository: https://github.com/Wangchimei/TripHub

Demo: https://trip-hub.herokuapp.com/

Learning Schedule

Vue.js, Vue CLI, Vuetify, Firebase

A weekend project to explore Vue.js and Firestore. This web app was created to plan future study schedule in web development.

GitHub repository: https://github.com/Wangchimei/dev-learning-calendar

CERTIFICATIONS

TOEIC 950 points (Dec 2016)

Japanese Language Proficiency Test N1 (Dec 2017)